Finding Aid for the John Gilmore Papers LSC.1144
UCLA Library Special Collections
John Gilmore papers
circa 1965
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gilmore, John
LSC.1144
14.2 Linear Feet (29 boxes and 2 oversize boxes)
John Gilmore (1935- ) was a instructor in creative writing at Antioch College/West and Glendora College (1974-76) and a author. The collection contains research materials for manuscripts and published copies of Gilmore's works, including the Tucson murders, The garbage people, Blowout, and the screenplay, Indiana twilight. Also contains photographs, clippings, diary entries, correspondence, and publicity materials.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Gilmore, 1974-89.
Gift of Laurance Rivera, 1994.
Gift of Marie NaVeaux, 1997.
Boxes 22-28 gift of Diana Levitt Herbert, 2007
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9914705723606533
Biography
Gilmore was born on July 5, 1935 in Los Angeles; became a child actor in Hollywood during the 1940s; attended New York University; BA, Antioch College, 1955; later became a leading man, acting in film, television, and on the New York stage; instructor in creative writing at Antioch College/West and Glendora College, 1974-76; won New York Circle Award for Poetry, 1967, and Southwest Literary Award in 1976 for his novel, Blowout; other publications include Overpass blues (1967), The Tucson murders (1970), The garbage people (1971), The real James Dean (1975), and Night shark (1975).
Scope and Content
Collection contains research materials for and manuscripts and published copies of John Gilmore's works, including the Tucson murders, The garbage people, Blowout, and the screenplay, Indiana twilight. Also contains photographs, clippings, diary entries, correspondence, and publicity materials.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
The garbage people (Boxes 1-4)
The Tucson murders (Boxes 5,12).
James Dean writings, photographs and ephemera (Boxes 5,7).
Miscellaneous manuscripts (Boxes 6,15).
Miscellaneous photographs and ephemera (Box 6).
Wings, Bad losers, poems (Box 7).
Blowout (Boxes 8-9).
Miscellaneous diary entries, unpublished stories (Box 9).
Indiana twilight (Boxes 10-11).
Black Dahlia photographs (oversize, box 13).
Black Dahlia, Shooting stars (Boxes 14-16).
Severed, Desperation point, Signals, Santa Fe blond, Damaged man, and other material (Boxes 17-18).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: John Gilmore Papers (11 items).
Authors, American -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Manuscripts for publication; Gilmore, John, 1935- --Archive
- The Garbage People
  Scope and Contents note
  (Manuscripts, research material and publication material)
  - The Garbage people, ca. 1970.; 278 leaves. Typescript with paste-on and holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    This copy lacks final changes in manuscript and "Vigil for Manson" which appears in the publication.
  - Another copy., (Photocopy). (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - "Burning is the end - dispatch from the pit of death - in trilogy", ca. 1970.; xiii, 102 leaves. Lacks leaf i. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Written (from different points of view) for John Gilciore as an appendix to The Garbage people.
    Concerns Beausoleil's philosophy of death and superiority.
  - --- -----, Another typing of leaves. 4-18., 15 leaves. numbered 3-18. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Death Row interview, ca. 1970.; [35] leaves. Holograph (photocopy) and typescript. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Transcription of notes from San Quentin interview Beausoleil.
  - "You are the stranger: Charles Manson at Los Angeles County Jail", ca. 1970.; 39 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 1, Folder 8)
    (From 9 interviews with Charles Manson)
  - Grand Jury transcript of the Charles Manson murder trials (Charles Hanson's copy) signed by Charles Manson (2 vol.); research material for The Garbage people, 1969.; 384 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - The Garbage people. Los Angeles: Omega Press, 1971.; l87pp. [2 copies]. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Another copy., (Wrappers). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Saigon Post, Wednesday October 20, 1971.; 1 leaf (clipping). (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Excerpt from The Garbage people.
  - La Gente de las basura. Mexico, D.F.: Editorial extemporaneos, 1972.; 248pp. [2 copies]. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The Tucson Murders
  - The Tucson murders, 1960s[?].; 436 leaves. Type script with paste-on and holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    "First draft"
  - First notes, Schmid case, dated: (Westerner Hotel, Arizona)., Saturday February 19, 1966; 25 leaves. Carbon typescript with some holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Materials from a notebook kept by John Gilmore, 1966 and n.d. (Box 3)
    Miscellaneous notes, transcripts of Charles Schmid's jail letters, first draft materials for The Tucson murders.
  - The 'Little House' at Florence., 5 leaves. Carbon typescript. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Portions of a work in progress: Charles Schmid., 27 leaves. Typescript. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    An account of teenage murders in Tucson, Arizona, and the story of the accused.
  - Cold complex., 15 leaves. Typescript. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Transcript [Testimony of Richard Bruns]., 11 leaves. Carbon typescript. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Pima County Jail.", 10 leaves. Carbon typescript. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Miscellaneous notes]., 54 leaves. Typescript. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - A Grave near the end of the greens., 162 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Copies of letters to his wife, 1965-66.; [68] leaves. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Decline of teenage morals., 11 leaves. Typescript (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Copies of correspondence, statements, etc., [57 leaves] numbered in pencil 84-140. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Police description of Alleen Rowe., 1 leaves. Typescript. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Schmid, Charles[?] Copy of diary[?]., 3 leaves. Typescript with paste-on corrections. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Second theme., 15 leaves. Typescript with minor holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Schmid notes. Los Angeles, July 26, 1967.; 90 leaves. Typescript. (leaves 61-90 are photocopies). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - KCUB News interview with Charles Schmid at Death Row, Arizona State Penitentiary (Tucson), April 14, 1966.; 22 leaves. Typescript. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Transcripts pertaining to The State of Arizona, plaintiff, vs. Charles H. Schmid, Jr., defendant (no.A-15028). Tucson, 1966.; 99 leaves (Carbon typescript) and l6 leaves (Carbon typescript). (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Transcript of testimony of Richard Bruns.
    Opening statements of William J. Schaefer, III and William K. Tinney, Jr. Tucson, 1966.
    Each signed by court reporter.
  - Pressbook clippings on Schmid murder case., November 11, 1965-June 20, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
    re Tucson murders (all news clippings and wire service).
  - Photographs pertaining to the Schmid case., 15 items. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs used as illustrations for The Tucson murders., 19 items. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Publisher's announcement for The Tucson murders, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Tucson murders. New York: Dial Press, 1970.; 274pp. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Also, 2 reel-to-reel tapes:
    1) With R. Burns - Charles Schmid's closest friend was an informer in murders. Tape: John Gilmore and Richie Bruns. Tucson, July 1967.
    2) Charles Schmid, John Gilmore and George Scott. Schmid interview (spliced master). Death Row, Arizona State Penitentary. Recorded Thursday April 14.
  - Fact sheet, Schmid-Saunders-French Case. Compiled by Hudson, 31 January 1966.; [i], 20 [2] leaves. Typescript. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    With tipped-in newspaper clippings.
  - Newspaper clippings, March 1975. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    re the death of Charles Schmid, while imprisoned.
  - Letter from Gary Greenberg to John Gilmore, accompanying newspaper clippings above, March 1975[?]. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Pied piper, March 17, 1970.; [ii] 130 leaves. Typescript (mimeograph). (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Final draft.
    Based on The Tucson murders by John Gilmore ... and action picture treatment by John Gilmore, [titled] Charles Schmid.
    Released October 1971 under title The Todd killings.
  - Another copy., Lacks leaves 124-130. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - What are we going to do without Skipper?, April 14, 1970.; 122 leaves. Typescript (mimeograph). (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Revised final draft.
    Based on The Tucson murders. Released October 1971, National General under title The Todd killings.
- James Dean
  Writings by John Gilmore; Photographs and Ephemera
  - James Dean: the rebel recalled., [5] leaves. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    From April 1975 issue of Gallery.
  - The real James Dean. Los Angeles, 1974[?].; [l]p. leaves. i, 225 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The real James Dean. New York: Pyramid Books, July 1975.; 160pp. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photographs., 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Used as illustrations for The Real James Dean.
  - Photographs marked "re: The Real James Dean.", 5 items. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    One photo is marked "re: The Real Janes Dean article syndicated London Express"
    These do not appear in the Pyramid Books publication.
  - Photographs of James Dean, n.d.; 7 items. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Still, from East of Eden and candid photos taken on Warner Brothers lot.
  - Miscellaneous James Dean-related items. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Photographs of life mask of James Dean and of James Dean's motorcycle jacket and tee-shirt.
  - Night circuit. Hollywood, 1961.; 124 leaves. Carbon typescript. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Story and screenplay. First draft.
  - The real James Dean. New York, 1975.; 53 leaves. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Uncorrected galley proofs.
  - 25 years after his death...author reveals...clippings from Hollywood Star, n.d.; 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    General note
    (Added October 1980)
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts By John Gilmore
  - "Too near to hear the harp." Los Angeles[?], 1962.; 64 leaves. Typescript with extensive holograph corrections. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Episode for Naked city.
  - "Breaking hard." Los Angeles?, 1965.; 95 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Story and screenplay. Revised draft, May 13, 1965.
    With this: First treatment, February 1965. 16 leaves. Typescript (Incomplete).
  - Faces by John Murdoch (pseudonym). Los Angeles[?], 1966.; 118 leaves. Carbon typescript with extensive holograph corrections. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Story and screenplay.
  - Faces. Los Angeles[?], 1966.; 76 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    "Writer's draft."
  - The human trap. Los Angeles[?], 1967.; iv, 97 leaves. Typescript (offset?). (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - What Are We Doing. Los Angeles, 1969; (Typescript with holograph corrections).
    The following folders are materials kept in the order in which John Gilmore placed them in looseleaf binder.
    Each manuscript is a version of what was in the end titled What are we doing, where are we going.
    - Changes [Revisions]
      - [Treatment of opening scene]., 9 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - [Treatment]., 20 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Story outline., 16 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Film step outline., 31 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Opening [treatment]., [4] leaves. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - [Draft, written as screenplay]., 53 leaves. with 7 leaves. (photocopy) inserted. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - What are we doing, where are we going., 56 leaves. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous drafts of scenes, notes for scenes, etc., Various pagings. [20] leaves. (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Photographs and Ephemera Relating to John Gilmore
  - Impression (Blues for Willie). Photographs (production and stills) of movie written-directed by John Gilmore, 1961.; 16 items. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Photographs mounted on posterboard: "Hollywood and Vine in the early 1950's" and "John Gilmore leaning on his Mercury in ", 1952. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, ephemera., 1960, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "Wings"
  Source Material.
  (Article by John Gilmore, to be published)
  - Ingalls, Laura. [Autobiography]. In 3 parts. n.p., n.d.
    - [Part 1] "Air express." n.p., n.d.; 22 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - [Part 2] Untitled., 69 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - [Part 3] "Up with the wind.", 38 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Memo from Carlos Drake to Laura Ingalls, March 1954.; 9 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Holograph notes by Laura Ingalls, n.d.; 2 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Laura Ingalls., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Material about airplanes and Laura Ingalls. Clipping concerning Laura Ingalls, 1941.; Photocopies. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Typed explanatory note by John Gilmore.
- Bad Losers
  Manuscripts, Source Material
  - Bad Losers. Los Angeles[?], 1973-74.; Various pagings, ca. 350 leaves. Typescripts with extensive holograph and paste-on corrections. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Two photographs ("Josie's farmhouse, Modesto"; "Hospital, Modesto") and 3 credit card receipts. Letter from author: "part of inception on this book, or rather this particular draft." (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Poems By John Gilmore
  - Francine. Los Angeles, 1975[?].; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Francine. Los Angeles, 1975[?]. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    In: Purr, issue no.3, 1975.
  - Desert storm. Los Angeles, 1975[?].; 1 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Desert storm. n.p., n.d.; 1 leaf. Photocopy. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    "Northwoods" printed at the bottom (Magazine in which published[?]).
- Additions To Collection, December 1975
  - The real James Dean. Los Angeles, 1974[?].; [l]p. leaves. 225 leaves. Typescript with extensive holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Also, letter from Barbara Shepherd (John Gilmore's agent): "the original, finalized manuscript ... containing all corrections and editing for press. ... The editor on this book was Mark Howell. The very first, or title page, is missing (lost in press)."
  - Newsprint clippings from unidentified publication re Riding the snake. n.p., n.d.; 2 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Non Fiction
  - Black Dahlia
    - Research Material
      - Photographs of family, detectives, suspects. etc., 1940s. (Box 13, Folder 1)
        [FLAT BOX NOT FULL]
      - Photocopies of articles and photos, 1940s-1950s. (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      - Photocopies, 1940s[?]. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Photographs, 1940s-. (Box 15, Folder 1)
        Many are newspaper photos with "whiteout."
    - Manuscript Material
      - Draft (incomplete), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bradley Marc Minkoff
    - Research material, etc. (Box 14)
      Also, correspondence with Minkoff.
      [This material removed from Box 13 to Box 14]
  - Severed
    - Manuscript
      - JG: Final, minus corrections to New York., 1993.; ca. 330 leaves. With photocopies of illustrations. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Research Material
      - Clippings., 1947 and v.d.; Photocopies. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Georgette Bauerdorf murder., 1944.; Clippings (photocopies). (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Autopsy papers, coroner's inquest, police and sheriff records, interviews by JG, etc., 1940s-1980s. (Box 17, Folder 1)
        Scope and Contents
        A 48 page interview with Arnold Smith, also known as Jack Anderson Wilson, is included in this folder.
    - Publication Material
      - Corrected page proofs, printer's copy., 1994 January 28. (Box 18, Folder 1)
        With mock up of cover.
      - Second proofs., 1994 March. (Box 18, Folder 2)
        Also, list of corrections.
      - Third and final proofs, uncorrected. (Box 18, Folder 3)
        Incorporate changes from second proofs.
      - Copy of book, Zanja Press., 1994. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Research and Publication Material
      - Photocopies, copies of photographs, correspondence with publishers, etc., 1940s-1990s. (Box 18, Folder 4)
        Photographs of: Robert Manley, Ursula Gilmore and Barbara Lee, etc.
    - Publication Material
      - Article about John Gilmore, incomplete., 1962. (Box 18, Folder 5)
        Cf. copy of article in Publicity folder.
    - Publicity
      - Draft for publicity packet, 1993. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Live Fast - Die Young: Remembering the short life of James Dean
    - Post-Publication Material
      - Publicity, etc., ca. 1997.; Primarily photocopies. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Publication Material
      - New York: Thunder's Mouth Press, 1997. (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Uncorrected proof copy in wrappers, ca. 1997. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Final manuscript, with corrections, line edition by press., 1997. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Completed line edit, proof and changes [printer's copy]., 1997. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - First proof, before galley corrections., 1997. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript Material
      - Author's proposal, 1996. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Hollywood Stars
    Diane Varsi, Ina Balin
    - Research Material
      - Clippings and correspondence, 1993. (Box 20, Folder 3)
        Primarly obituary information.
        Also photographs (photocopies) by JG of DV.
- Fiction
  - Tucson Murders
    - Publication Material
      - In: Dial Press announcement, 1970. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Santa Fe Blonde
    - Manuscript Material
      - Various drafts, 1992. (Box 17, Folder 2)
        JG notes was accepted by Paris Review and Fiction Quarterly.
  - Laid Bare
    - Research Material
      - Copy of book by Barbara Payton, I am not ashamed. Holloway House, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Various Titles
    - Manuscript Material
      - [Miscellaneous titles], 1963-1979 (inclusive). (Box 16, Folder 5)
        All titles: "The exterminator," "Losing ground," "Verge of overload," "The mountain" (screenplay treatment), "The wrecking crew" (novel outline).
  - Desperation Point
    - Manuscript Material
      - Novel (unpublished), 1967. (Box 16, Folder 7)
        Rough draft.
  - Signals
    - Manuscript
      - Various drafts, 1966. (Box 16, Folder 9)
        Published in California review of literature.
  - Damaged Man
    - Pre-Manuscript Material
      - Notes, 1976, 1978. (Box 17, Folder 6)
        Note from JG: "See Kidnap notes, crossover between projects."
  - Swamp Blood
    (Novel in progress)
    - Manuscript Material
      - Copy, by Jack McFaren (pseudonym), 1993. (Box 20, Folder 1)
        Based on JG's screenplay of same title.
  - The Prisoner
    - Manuscript Material
      - Copy, 1963. (Box 19, Folder 3)
        Set in Army stockade, 1954.
- Motion Pictures
  - Shooting Stars
    - Manuscript Material
      - Original script, 1985 April-May. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Sujet et scenario, 1985. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Copy, by J.C. Carriere, John Gilmore, and Malcolm Karman., 1985. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Laura Ingalls
    - Manuscript Material
      - Copy of work by Ingalls, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
        Also negative of LI[?].
        See other sections of JG papers, e.g. Box 7.
    - Research Material
      - Copies of information about Julia Kraus, 1940s. (Box 15, Folder 7)
        Also information about America First committee.
  - The Last Low Rider
    - Manuscript Material
      - Treatment (original), 1990. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Deathtrip
    - Manuscript Material
      - Original story and screenplay, 1986-1987. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - James Dean
    - Manuscript Material
      - Story, 1990. (Box 20, Folder 4)
        Based on JG's The real James Dean.
      - First draft, 1990. (Box 20, Folder 5)
        Fictionalized version from JG's book and personal materials, intended for feature produced by UI.
  - Swamp Blood
    - Manuscript Material
      - Story and screenplay. Copy, with letter., 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Additions To Collection, August 1976
- Blowout By John Gilmore
  Manuscripts
  See also Box 7, folder 8-9, under Bad losers, the first title of this novel.
  - Blowout. Los Angeles, 1975.; Various pagings, ca. 150 leaves. Typescript (original, carbon, photocopy) with holograph and paste-on corrections. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    "Chapters are not consecutive, and various chaptars throughout are not included (missing or disposed of by Mr. Gilmore)" - letter from Carol Barry, in Collections File.
  - -----. n.p., n.d.; 472 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections and additions and paste-on additions. (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
    First completed draft:
    Folder 2) leaves 1-131.
    Folder 3) leaves 152-290.
    Folder 4) leaves 291-472.
  - -----, n.p., June 1976.; 346 leaves. Typescript with holograph and paste-on corrections. (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    Second draft:
    Folder 1) leaves 1-139.
    Folder 2) leaves 190-345.
  - -----, n.p., 1976.; 291 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Incorporates corrections of second draft and corrections and editorial revisions in press.
- Miscellaneous Diary Entries, Unpublished Stories, etc.
  (Folder titles are based on notes received with material)
  - Letters, diary entries (1954), prose-descriptions, etc. Most materials are actually from, 1964. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Leopard for rent, n.p., n.d.; 9 leaves. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Published in Rogue, 1960.
  - Prose fragments, 1961-63. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Diary notes, story ideas, 1964. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, July 3-November 16, 1964. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Diary entries, 1965-1968. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Diaries, prose descriptions, notes, etc., 1966. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Letter to New York actress Marilyn Roberts, May 4, 1966. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Diary entries, January-June 1967. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Story "Cyclone", 1967. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    (Unpublished)
  - Miscellaneous notes, diaries, letters, etc., 1967. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Carbon of letter to Garry [Greenberg], August 7, 1975. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Additions To Collection, August 1931
- Indiana Twilight, 1979-80
  Drafts, notes, manuscript, screenplay.
  (Folder descriptions adapted from notes by the author)
  - Lie down in darkness by H.R. Hayes., ca. 100 leaves. Photocopy. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    With JG's holograph notes in preparation for first draft screenplay.
  - First notes for screenplay based on changes in novel, adapting for motion picture., [29] leaves. Holograph and typescript. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notes for changes in concept, ideas, based on story conferences., 11 leaves. Holograph. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - First draft (writer's work draft) based on notes and novel excerpts., [141] leaves. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Also, 1 leaf unrelated holograph notes.
  - First draft (writer's work draft) with changes for 2nd draft., Various pagings, ca. 141 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Further notes for changes in first draft (from story conferences and Gilmore's new changes) in preparation for 2nd draft., 20 leaves. Holograph. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ideas, scenes for 2nd draft., 31 leaves. Holograph and typescript. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Second draft (writer's work draft) with new title Indiana twilight; incorporates changes in this draft by Gilmore., Various pagings, ca. 165 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections (photocopy). (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Second draft (work draft) with revisions by John Gilmore and Curtis Harrington, director., January-February 1980.; Various pagings, ca. 175 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 11, Folder 1)